[Music]
this was a very rundown area of seafront
in an area of deprivation when the life
expectancy in this Ward uh is 10 years
lower than the average life expectancy
in the rest of Bourn this is a 50-year
old building that was built as a bathing
station 10 years ago it was a a land
train garage an amusement arcade and
some pretty crummy toilets and some
Beach hats above that we never used I do
remember how it was before bosam had
become a really rundown area had quite a
bad reputation locally it was always
very quiet it was kind of a a nogo area
before we had lots of problems with
deviant Behavior alcohol drugs and so on
so this was all pretty run down it's
like a 1950s building and it looked it
the council's been trying to regenerate
boson for 30 years
putting the surf Reef out to seea this
being the landbased Leisure was the real
opportunity to regenerate
[Music]
what started on the sea front will
trickle back into the center of bosam
and is beginning to the change on the
sea front has been immense The Reef is
the economic driver principally it would
work in Bournemouth um in the winter and
it would provide a lagoon in the summer
and we thought well that'll actually
help us to trade all year it was a
catalyst for for all of this investment
along the seafront re located offshore
of the overstrand complex where we're
sitting so the idea was to have a
panoramic restaurant with uh sea views
overlooking the reath we've got a
residential development which I think we
can be very proud of it's very popular a
refurbished Pier everyone wanted to
retain the pier I moved down here
because of the changes that's been
happening it's it's such a good place to
live it's such a good vibe down here I'm
really enjoying being a part of the surf
culture my name's Sean Taylor I own
sorted Surf Shop sorted surf school down
here on boson Beach we have people
coming down to check out the The Reef
we've got people coming down to Surf The
Reef um check the area out they've heard
about the new stores bars we've got
people looking at buying property in the
area it's the surf lessons business
that's really surprised them and
generally I'm people are taking
beginners lessons on very small waves um
they wouldn't be here but for the fact
we've got the reath as well there's so
much attention from non Surfers and
Surfers as well you know um Surfers come
and ask a little bit more in depth
questions non Surfers come down and want
to know what the big hype's about it's
fantastic for the area just because
we've seen such a big development since
Britain's got a really good strong
surfing industry and things like this
will actually make it you know even
stronger there's a lot of people coming
around from all over the country
families holidaying name it is happening
down here but it's a much much more
chilled atmosphere now than it used to
be the publicity value of what we've
done here we we've estimated already at
million um a lot of that's been
attributable to the reef and that's
based on the advertising equivalent cost
of the publicity that we've achieved I
didn't used to really come to boson but
I come down here quite a lot more now
since kind of the surf roof and
everything like that and it's being done
up down here it's just it brings in a
new crowd everything's very roof based I
mean there's a reef encounter which has
got quite a few nights on and things
like that it's definitely been busier
since the announcement of the reef
people are wandering this way from
Bournemouth um and further away around
over to pool the day we decided to uh
include a reath within this project a
hotel Redevelopment was renamed the reef
and since then we've had the wave we've
got retail restaurant Reef encounter
we've got this restaurant here called
Urban Reef um so lots of developers and
and um commercial outlets have uh have
have used that as part of their
marketing we're at the urban Reef Cafe
Bar and restaurant which is right the
heart of the over strand development
opposite bosom's new surf Reef it's
become a real case study for Coastal
regeneration The Reef was probably the
Catalyst for that and then with the
Regeneration of the pier and the
overstand building itself has made local
Flats been invested in I don't think the
people can believe it really you know
you came down here 18 months ago and it
was a pretty rundown stretch of Beach
and now it's beautiful you can sit
outside have a nice kind of kiwi bottle
of Savon Blanc some fresh mus
and it's got a really really nice
vibrant atmosphere so the finishing
result I'm just about there is is very
pleasing the change is so dramatic and
it's it's done so much for bourou the
Redevelopment of the sea front has
really made it such a nice place to live
and I don't think I want to leave one of
the key issues for you know other
Resorts who might want to do this is
that this whole project will have been
funded by the sale of the res itial land
and the sale of the beach pods so it's
not actually costing the council
taxpayer anything and just to come down
here now and just see people enjoying
themselves being part of the New Boston
star Village is without doubt already
giving a new confidence to Boston that
hasn't been there for for 30 years
[Music]